Nikolaos Liliakidis

Brighton, East Sussex, BN2 9YF

Mobile: 07575855085 Email: nickliliakides@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://nickliliakides.github.io/nikolaosliliakidis.github.io/
Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nick-liliakides-820a7236/
GitHub:https://github.com/nickliliakides

Personal Profile

I'm an ambitious, flexible, hardworking and experienced software engineer, passionate around React ecosystem and focused on learning the latest and hottest technologies in the industry, as well comfortable on building RESTful APIs from scratch using MERN stack and with great attention to detail. I have been interested in programming and computing since I was nine years old and this led me to complete an IT Degree in my home country, Just IT self-funded professional web developer course and my passion for learning new languages and technologies stayed imperishable, continuing to gain educational experiences in completion of IT degree at the UK's Open University.

I'm seeking to undertake software development challenges, full responsibly, for personal and career development. My first priority or next step is to see myself at the Senior level as soon as possible gaining through my employment new skills and knowledge to progress further my career within a challenging environment.

Education and IT Training

07/2017-01/2018

Just IT Training Ltd, London Development Professional Programme

- MTA Software Development Fundamentals (Expected 2017)
- MTA HTML5 Web Application Development Fundamentals (Expected 2017)
- MCSD Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 (Expected 2017)
- MCSD Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Application (Expected 2017)

08/2014-06/2020 The Open University, UK

Bachelor Degree - BSc (Honours) Computing and IT, Part Time

Core Modules: Sense Programming, Robotics (Robotlab programming simulator)

Microsoft Networking, Linux, Maths, Web Technologies

Languages: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Python. SQL

08/2011-08/2012 BHMS, Business and Hotel Management School Lucerne Switzerland

Post Graduate Diploma in Hospitality and Business Management

09/2001-06/2003 National Institute of Professional Training and Education Thessaloniki, Greece Certified Degree in "Applications Technician on ITs and Networks"

Core Modules: MS Office (Word, Excel, Access), Pascal, Visual-Basic, C++, Unix, SQL, Networking Essentials, Maths, Computer Hardware Essentials

IT Skills

Development Core Skills: JavaScript-TypeScript, React, Redux, Node, Express, Docker, MongoDB, SQL

Web Technologies and Frameworks: HTML5, CSS-SASS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, MaterialUI, ASP.Net

Core Programming Languages: JavaScript-TypeScript, C#, Python, Java

Operating Systems: Mac OS X, Linux, Microsoft Windows, Android, iOS

Projects:	

Some of my demonstrative purposes projects are presented on my portfolio website

"https://nickliliakides.github.io/nikolaosliliakidis.github.io/" in Projects section where the visitors can see description, demonstration and links to read the code in Github.

Employment History

05/2021-Now

Inviqa, London, UK - https://inviqa.com/ Frontend engineer (pemanent)

- Building and maintaining bespoke digital solutions for company's clients.
- Technologies: Next.js, Typescript, TailwindCSS, Storybook, GraphQL, Drupal, Docker.
- Testing: Jest, React testing library, Puppeteer and Cypress for integration tests.
- Methodologies: Agile Kanban.

10/2020-04/2021 Sportbuff, London, UK - https://sportbuff.com/ Frontend engineer (pemanent)

- Building company's dashboards(Content, Admin and Metrics).
- Technologies: React, Redux(Thunk-Sagas), Typescript.
- Testing: Jest, Enzyme for unit tests Cypress for integration tests.
- Methodologies: Agile Scrum.

10/2019-08/2020 WinMan ERP Software, Brighton, UK - https://www.winman.com/ Frontend UI developer (permanent)

- Building and improving the UI of company's main ERP software cloud application.
- Technologies: HTML, CSS-Sass, Javascript(React-Redux-Vanilla-JQuery), C#, Razor pages.
- Frameworks: ASP.Net Core, Bootstrap, SyncFusion, Datatables.js, Chart.js
- Source control using Git, Visual Studio integrated Git tool plus command line.
- Methodologies: Agile Scrum.

12/2018-08/2019 R3ality Projects, Brighton, UK - https://www.realityprojects.co.uk Frontend developer (contract)

- Developing a gas company client management application.
- Core libraries and frameworks used: React, Redux, MaterialUI, Jest and Enzyme.
- Basic React template Fuse2 and source control via git and sourcetree.
- Other libraries used: axios, moxios, lodash, react-dropzone, react-table etc.

08/2017-10/2022 Hermes Web Development(HWD My LTD), London - Brighton, UK Founder/Director/Full-stack Developer

- Creating e-commerce solutions and web applications using MERN stack. (HTML, CSS-SaSS, JavaScript, React-Redux, Node-Express, MongoDB-Mongoose).
- Seeking and finding suitable domain, database and hosting services for our clients.
- Supporting, upgrading and maintaining our creations.

03/2018-04/2018 Farmco International, Watford, UK – https://farmcointernational.com Web Developer (8 weeks internship placement)

- ASP.Net Core Unit Testing.
- Testing and debugging code of Company's leading upcoming projects.

02/2013-10/2016 E-Business Solutions, Thessaloniki, Greece Web Developer(Remote part-time)

- Supporting new businesses to be established.
- Web design and development(Mainly used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, MicrosoftSQL).
- Digital Marketing, consulting and technical support.

10/2012-07/2017 The Real Greek, Spitalfields Market, London, UK Restaurant Supervisor/Assistant Manager

- Organizing and cooperating with front and back of the house to run busy shifts smoothly.
- Dealing with 'difficult' customers and complaints and solving problems that occur.
- Banking and closing daily shifts, reporting and sending numbers and stats to the head office and operations inputting stock, orders and invoices into the company's database system.

02/2004-07/2011 Digital DVD movies, videogames, Internet Cafe and IT services Thessaloniki, Greece Owner, Director, General Manager

- Selling and renting movies, video-games and data media.
- Providing a Local Area Network for customers and groups to surf the web and play online games.
- Providing technical support on software and hardware of desktop and mobile devices.
- Developing company's website using Dreamweaver.

Interests and Achievements

Computing: Since I was 9 years old I was writing programs on Basic and playing games on my AMSTRAD CPC 6128 or my friend's Spectrum, Commodore 64 and a bit later Atari ST and Amiga game consoles back to 80s and 90s. Since early on 21th century I use Internet and computers in a more advanced level and I also studied and became software, hardware and network technician. I use very efficient plenty of Operating systems, application and services like: Microsoft Windows, Mac OS, Linux, Microsoft Office, Visual Studio, Adobe Photoshop, Ableton, Sound Forge, Social Media, Remote connection services and many more. Except technologies and Web I have a big passion for music(mixing and production), cinema, sports and quality food.

References available upon request